前情提要
丘吉尔阁下
Mr Churchill...
如果真要弄死一些人
If there are bodies to be buried,
就挖洞深埋起来  要干净利落
dig holes and dig them deep.
别当着我妻儿的面抓我
Don't do this in here.
你们要将我从儿子面前带走吗
You're taking me away from my baby!
-弗莱迪  -艾达
- Freddie! - Ada!
出卖弗莱迪·索恩的人不是我
It wasn't me who shopped Freddie Thorne.
他信任我  我告诉过你这一点
He trusts me. I told you that.
我想我知道枪藏在哪里了
I think I know where the guns are hidden.
我要你保证  如果枪找到了
I want your word that Thomas Shelby will not be harmed
你不能伤害汤玛斯·谢尔比
if the guns are recovered.
如果能跟你合作真的很荣幸  肯波先生
It would be an honour to work with you, Mr Kimber.
没人可以跟我合作  都只能在我手下工作
Nobody works with me. People work for me.
一颗黑星  这是什么意思
A black star? What does that mean?
标上黑星那天
The black star day
是我们除掉比利·肯波和他的手下的日子
is the day we take out Billy Kimber and his men.
格蕾丝  你愿意嫁给我吗
Grace...will you marry me?
你可以找到比我更好的
You deserve better.
是因为他吗
Is it him?!
-他在哪儿  -他走了
- Where is he? - He left.
和酒吧女招待一起
With the barmaid.
服务生
Service.
我们两小时后才营业  你晚点再过来
We don't open two more hours. You come back later.
警察
Police.
您是坎贝尔督察啊  先生
Inspector Campbell, sir.
我们有什么麻烦了吗
Any trouble, sir?
听着
Look...
我知道
I know.
我知道的
就是  我手下的好几个警官告诉我
That is, I am given to understand by several of my officers...
我手下的好几名警官说  很多人到这里来
several of my officers, that people come here...
男人会到这里来
That men come here for...
寻求某种慰藉
a certain purpose.
亚瑟  亚瑟  醒醒
Arthur? Arthur, wake up.
回家去  洗个澡
Get home, get bathed.
检查一下装备和武器
Check your kit, check your weapons.
为什么
Why?
出什么事了
What's going on?
我们今天就要开干了
We're doing it today.
准备好马车  查理
Fetch the wagons, Charlie.
就今天了
It's today.
爸爸  凯蒂又在床上撒尿了
Dad? Our Katie's done a wee in the bed again.
我马上就来处理  小家伙
I'll be there in a minute, mate.
约翰  我告诉过你要记得锁门
John, I've told you to keep the doors locked.
冲进来的可能是任何人
It could've been anyone.
穿上衣服
Get dressed.
我们今天就开干了
We're doing it today.
事实上  他今天的任务就是干我
As a matter of fact, he's doing me today.
务必让他在9点前干完你
Make sure he's done you by nine.
你该学会敲门
You should learn to knock!
今天不是敲门的日子
It's not a day for knocking.
上帝啊  一定要让今天顺利度过
Dear Lord, make this day pass well.
不要让任何人受伤
Let none get hurt
即使有人受伤  也不要是谢尔比家族的人
and make them that do not Shelbys.
照看好约翰
Watch John,
有好几个孩子依靠着他
cos he has so many depending on him.
照看好亚瑟
Watch Arthur
因为除了别人会伤害他  他也会伤害自己
because he's as likely to hurt himself as anyone else.
照看好汤玛斯
Watch Thomas.
我知道他是什么样的人
I know how he is.
但他做出那些事都是为了我们
But he does what he does for us.
我觉得是
I think.
阿门
Amen.
我在战时每天早晨都祈祷
I used to do that every morning during the war.
我曾希望我可以最后一次祈祷就完事了
I hoped I'd done it for the last time.
今天就是你最后一次祈祷了  波莉
Today will be the last time, Poll.
过了今天  就没必要再祈祷了
After today, there'll be no need for prayers.
我们就安定了
We'll be set.
十点半  家族会议
Family meeting, half ten.
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季终   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第六集
我很抱歉让您久等了  现在真的很早
I'm sorry I kept you. It is so early.
是的  我...
Yes. I-I...
我昨晚一直没睡
I didn't sleep last night.
张先生说你是个很特殊很特殊的客人
Mr Zhang said you are special, special customer.
你想坐下吗
Do you want to sit?
你想脱掉靴子吗
Do you want to take off your boots?
是的
Yes.
还有  这个
And...this.
系得好紧啊
So tight.
我们欢好时  可以让人帮你把衣服洗干净熨烫下
We can also clean and press your shirt while we do this.
你们的服务效率可真高
That's a very efficient service.
你以前从没来过这种地方吗
You never been to a place like this before?
没关系的
It's OK.
有时候那些失去妻子的老男人也会到这里来
Sometimes old men who have lost their wives, they come here...
经常来的
all the time.
老男人
Old men?
我有那么老吗
I am so old?
不  我是说我很年轻
No! I mean I am young.
总之
Anyway...
我会让你也觉得恢复年轻状态的
I'll make you young as well.
婊子
Whore.
亲爱的格蕾丝
'Dear Grace.
我怀着沉重的心情给你写这封信
'I write this letter to you with a heavy heart.
我清楚地知道你干了什么  和谁一起干的
'I know exactly what you did, and with whom.
我在报告中一字都不会提的
'I will not mention any of it in my report.
但是  你必须明白
'However, you should be aware
我知道你已献身于我们不共戴天的仇敌
that I know you gave yourself to the man who is our sworn enemy.
那不仅是通敌行为
'That is not only treason,
更是恶心至极的行为
'it is disgusting beyond all measure.
你父亲一定会以你为耻的
'Your father would be ashamed of you.
至于我自己  我心痛不已
'And as for myself... I am beyond desolation.
你已经背叛了你生来就享有的
'You have betrayed every principle
一切荣耀和遵从的原则
'and standard of honour that was your birthright.
你又是为了什么呢
'And for what?'
爱
Love.
天啊  我很抱歉  那是我弄的吗
Oh, my God, I'm sorry. Did I do that?
没关系  你是位很特殊很特殊的客人
It's OK. You are special, special customer.
你能陪我坐一会儿吗
Would you sit with me for a moment?
求你了
Please.
衣服的钱
For the suits.
要听点有意思的消息吗
You want to hear something funny?
坎贝尔跟我的一个姑娘在里间
Campbell was in the back room with one of my girls.
我没带武器
I am unarmed.
真奇怪啊  督察
It's curious, Inspector.
我以为你是来清理这座城市的
I thought you came here to clean up the city.
而不是来跟妓女上床的
Not to sleep with its whores.
你跟之前来的警察没两样
You're no different from any other copper that came before you.
我和那些在我走后来接替我的人也没两样
I'm no different from those who would follow should I choose to leave.
你没理由留下
You've no reason to stay.
你的目的已经达到了
You have what you came for.
是的  我的目的达到了
Yes. I have what I came for.
我中午要和温斯顿·丘吉尔先生开会
I have a meeting with Mr Winston Churchill at midday.
无疑他会恭喜我
And no doubt he intends to congratulate me
寻回了那些被盗的枪支
on finding those stolen guns.
你还是不知道我们是怎么找到的  对吧
And you still don't know how we found them, do you?
很好
Good.
你走狗屎运罢了
Oh, you got lucky.
是吗
Did I?
是的
Yeah.
我学到的一件事
One thing I have learned...
就是你我既对立  又统一
is that you and I are opposites, but also just the same.
就好像镜中像
Like an image in a mirror.
我们讨厌别人
We hate people.
别人也讨厌我们
And they in turn hate us.
惧怕我们
And fear us.
今天  你会心碎
Before the day is over, your heart will be broken...
正如我一样
just the same as mine.
像我们这样的人  谢尔比先生
Men like us, Mr Shelby...
注定永远孤独
will always be alone.
我们得到的爱
And what love we get...
都必须付出代价
we will have to pay for.
你忘了  督察
You forget, Inspector.
我有家人
I have my family.
祝你今天过得愉快
Enjoy your day.
小家伙
Oh, little one...
你比我更会跟他相处
You're much better with him than I am.
他这么快就安静下来是因为我身上没有奶味
He settles quicker with me cos he can't smell the milk.
你累了  把他放回摇篮里吧
You're tired. Let's put him down.
我家孩子特爱咬乳头
Mine were terrors for the tit.
两个都是
Both of them.
你不认识我的孩子们吧
Well, you never knew my children, did you?
不  我自己当时都还是个孩子
No, I was a child myself, then.
你从没提起过
You never talk about them.
没理由说
Never had reason to.
一想到他们我就心疼
My heart breaks even when I think about them.
但今天
But today...
有理由了
I do have reason to.
坐下  艾达
Sit down, Ada.
他们一个三岁  一个五岁
They were three and five years old.
萨莉三岁  迈克尔五岁
Sally was three, Michael was five.
再过两周就六岁了
Two weeks away from being six.
那是周日早晨  我去教堂了
It was Sunday morning. I was at church.
"上帝不会原谅你"
"You're not forgiven."
一个苦瓜脸贱人跟我说  "上帝不会原谅你"
This... pinch-faced bitch said to me, "You're not forgiven."
我洗完晾在外面的床单上
You see, some sheets I washed and hung on the line
印着一家酒店的名字
had the name of a hotel on them.
那些床单在一件劫案中被偷
They'd been stolen in a robbery,
警方说酒店的服务员被人用短棍袭击了
and they said some porter at the hotel had been coshed.
附近有个女人把床单的事告诉了警方
And a woman from round here told the police about the sheets -
就是因为嫉妒我有新床单
jealous, you see, of the new sheets.
警察到来的时候
And when the police came,
发现一个用来制作杜松子酒的酒馏器
they found a spirit still for making a few drops of gin.
为此
And for that...
他们夺走了我的孩子们
They took my children from me.
也不告诉我将他们送去了哪
And they never told me where they took them.
他们这么做是因为他们有这个能力
And they did it cos they could.
因为我很软弱
And cos I was weak.
但他们绝不会夺走你的孩子
But they will never take your baby away from you.
知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
因为汤米不会让他们这么做
Cos Tommy wouldn't let them.
因为汤米不会让他们欺负我们
Cos Tommy won't let them walk all over us.
是汤米给了这个家族力量和权力
Now it is Tommy who has given strength and power to this family.
因为他知道
Cos he knows...
要生存就得比他们都凶狠
you have to be as bad as them above in order to survive.
我告诉你是因为我希望你能原谅他
I'm telling you this cos I want you to forgive him.
我怎么原谅他
How can I?
他害我的弗莱迪锒铛入狱
When my Freddie's rotting in jail because of him.
今天有些事你得知道
There's something about today you need to know.
好了  弗莱迪  该走了
All right, Freddie, time to go.
给坎贝尔传个信
I want to get a message to Campbell.
我绝不能被转去布里克斯顿
I can't let them move me to Brixton.
要是我去了那里  他们就会杀了我
If I go to Brixton, they'll kill me.
弗莱迪
Freddie.
你到不了布里克斯顿监狱的
You're not going to get as far as Brixton prison.
站起来
On your feet.
我亲自告诉首相
I told the Prime Minister personally
枪支已经寻回
that the guns had been retrieved
他真的认真听了
and he actually heard me and listened,
我很肯定他还微微一笑
and I'm pretty sure he gave me a half smile.
只有政敌死了他才会笑
He never usually smiles unless a political opponent dies.
我准备在新年授勋嘉奖名单中将你提前
I plan to put your name forward in the New Year's Honours list...
我受不起  长官
That would be too much, sir.
胡说  你应得的
Nonsense. You deserve it.
我记得你给我写过几封信
As I recall, you wrote to me several times
信中提到了一位女卧底
about an undercover operative. A woman.
寻回枪支一事  她出力了吗
Was she involved in the discovery?
值得我嘉奖她吗
Does she deserve some kind of commendation?
是的
Yes.
她帮了大忙
She was instrumental.
是王室忠诚的仆人
A truly loyal servant of the crown.
她的档案中必须记下这些杰出的表现
And that is what the record should state.
那些偷枪的人呢
And what of the men who actually stole the guns?
剃刀...
The Peaky...
党  长官
Blinders, sir.
如果去抓人
If we were to make arrests,
整件事就会曝光
the whole thing would end up in open court,
我深知您希望这件事能保密
and I know we wish to keep this matter confidential.
就这么放过他们吗
So they'll go free?
也不尽然  长官
Not quite, sir.
其实  我有针对剃刀党的计划
You see, I have plans for the Peaky Blinders.
你好啊
All right.
-你好  -你好啊  伙计
- All right. - All right, mate?
别弄了  晚点再来
Leave that, boys, come back to it later.
好了
Right.
今天我把大家召集在一起
I've brought you all here today
是因为今天我们将要取代比利·肯波
because this is the day we replace Billy Kimber.
从今天起我们将迈入上流社会
This is the day we become respectable.
今天我们将加入
The day we join
官方的全国赌马经营者协会
the official National Association of Race Course Bookmakers.
但首先
But first...
我们要干些不光彩的事
we do the dirty work.
我们都知道这一天迟早要来
We've all known it's been coming.
只是我从未说过具体是哪天
I just haven't told anyone the date.
我们出发去乌斯特赛马场
We're going to the Worcester races.
赛马场一点开门  我们两点到那
The track opens at one, we get there at two.
肯波以为我们去那
Now, Kimber thinks we're going there
是为了帮他对付李氏兄弟
to help him fight the Lee brothers.
但多亏了我们的约翰
But thanks to the efforts of our John,
以及他可爱的新婚妻子伊丝米
and his lovely new wife Esme,
现在李氏和我们是一家人了
the Lees are now our kin.
我今早打断了他们的好事
I interrupted those efforts this morning, and, er...
我向大家保证
I can assure you all,
约翰为和平大业做出了巨大的牺牲
John is making great sacrifices in the cause of peace.
好吧  行啦
Yeah, all right.
我们将和李氏家族一起对抗肯波的手下
So, it'll be us and the Lees against Kimber's boys.
我们干掉他们  把赌注经纪人留下
We take them out, then leave the bookies.
我希望能速战速决
I expect a swift victory
然后消息会传遍整个伦敦
which will send a signal all the way to London,
那就是我们相信
that we believe
可以和平地经营合法业务
in letting legitimate businesses run peacefully.
还有  肯波要怎么处理
And, er... what about Kimber himself?
我来处理肯波
I'll deal with Kimber.
还有别的问题吗
Any other questions?
有
Yes.
如果我带一个新人参加会议  有人反对吗
Oh, does anyone object if I bring a newcomer to the meeting?
进来吧
Come on.
容我向大家介绍谢尔比家族的新成员
I'd like to introduce the newest member of the Shelby clan.
欢迎回家  艾达
Welcome home, Ada.
我们给他起名叫卡尔
We named him Karl.
为纪念卡尔·马克思
After Karl Marx.
狗日的卡尔·马克思吗
Karl bloody Marx?
让我看看他
Let me get a look at him.
他又来了
Oh, here we go.
快看  他长得跟我简直一模一样
Eh, look. He looks just like me, look.
他的屁股长得像你吧  亚瑟
That's his arse looks like you, Arthur.
他帅着呢
He's all right.
他是谢尔比的一员
He's a Shelby.
艾达
Well, Ada?
你原谅我了吗
Am I forgiven?
如果波莉阿姨说的是真的  那我原谅你
If what Aunt Polly says is true, you are.
是真的
It's true.
谢谢你  汤米
Thank you, Tommy.
你到底是什么人
So, who the hell are you?
一个想保住自己眼睛的人
Someone who wants to keep his eyes.
他们跑到我家
They came to my house.
让我主动要求负责此事
Told me to volunteer for this.
他们是什么人
Who did?
是剃刀党
Peaky Blinders.
汤米啊汤米
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy...
别挡路
Get out of the way!
那他妈是怎么回事
What the bloody hell is that?
看来你的朋友到了
Looks like your friends are here.
趴在地上
Stay down on the ground.
否则一枪毙了你
Or the next one's for you.
下手狠一点
Make it look good.
我很抱歉  同志
I am sorry about this, comrade.
我的天啊
Holy shit.
丹尼  你不是死了吗
Danny, you're dead.
没  我一直住在伦敦  都是一码事
Nah. I've been living in London. Same thing.
你给我进去
In you get.
好了  伙计们  听我说
All right, lads, listen up.
你们只能喝一杯啤酒和姜汁酒  不要贪杯
You have a pint and a chaser, no more.
我请客
On the house.
很好  开始倒酒吧
Right. Let's get pouring.
你有观众席的票吗
Do you have the enclosure tickets?
以及赛马场所有簿记员的花名册
And the register of book-keepers on the track?
在我的大衣口袋里
In me coat.
你干的不错  格蕾丝
You did a good job, Grace.
就是那么回事  对吧
That's what it is, isn't it?
下次家族会议时  我会带你参加的
The next family meeting, I'll make sure you're there.
我要是你的家人才能去  但我不是
If I were family. But I'm not.
那是可以改变的
That could change.
汤米
Tommy...
等我回来我们再详谈  好吗
We'll talk about it more when I get back. All right?
你什么时候回来
When will you be back?
以后你都要这么问东问西了  对吗
Oh, is this how it's going to be, eh?
你在家里等我
You waiting at home for me,
问"你知道现在几点了吗"
saying, "What time do you call this?"
得换酒桶了
The barrel needs changing.
去吧  汤米  到后面去
Go on, Tommy, go out the back,
在我们走之前好好和她干一炮
give her a good seeing to before we go.
格蕾丝
Grace.
格蕾丝  我只是开玩笑
Hey, Grace, I was joking.
汤米  我们需要更多的淡啤
Tommy, we need more mild!
你们自己倒吧
Just help yourselves.
汤米  事实是
Tommy, the truth is
当你从赛场回来时  我已经离开了
when you come back from the races, I won't be here.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
好了
All right, look.
格蕾丝  我知道现在的自己配不上你
Grace, I know you weren't born to be with a man like me...
但我正在扭转这一局面
but I'm turning things around.
当我今晚回到这里时
And when I get back here tonight...
我将拥有全国数一数二的
I will have one of the biggest
合法赌马财团
legal racetrack syndicates in the country.
我也会了结其他一些事
And I'm going to close down some of that other stuff.
也许可以开个俱乐部
Maybe open a club, hey?
就像伦敦那样
Like in London.
另外就是
And another thing.
你有一份雇佣合同
You have a contract of employment.
跟一家真正的有限公司签的  还记得吗
with a real limited company. You remember?
我什么都记得  汤米
I remember everything, Tommy.
我会取得成功的
I am going to make a success of this.
我一定会成功的
I am going to make a success of it.
-我一定会  -我知道  知道
- I am. - I know. I know.
我现在不是在谈结婚的事
And I'm not talking about marriage.
我是
I'm...
我们彼此了解  真心交流
We know each other. We can talk.
我们是一样的人
We're the same...
汤米  我对你做了些可怕的事
Tommy, I have done something terrible to you.
把你刚告诉我的话转述给他
Right, tell him what you just told me.
我听说有两辆大蓬货车开到斯特拉福德路了
Just heard there's two vans driving up the Stratford Road.
我的一个旧下士认出了其中几个人
An old corporal of mine said he recognised some of the men.
他说是肯波的手下  他们正往这边来呢
He said it's Kimber boys, and they're heading this way.
艾达  快醒醒
Ada, wake up.
你带着孩子去斗牛场商业中心那边
You and the baby get into the Bull Ring,
那里人多
where there's lots of people.
-怎么回事  -我们他妈的被卖了
- What's going on? - We've been fucking betrayed.
有人走漏了风声  肯波的人正赶过来
Someone let slip. Kimber's men are on their way here.
即便如此  但你能对付他们的吧  汤米
Yeah, but you can handle them, Tommy?
只有我们在
It's just us.
李氏家族的人都在去乌斯特的路上  我们寡不敌众
All the Lees are on their way to Worcester. We're outnumbered.
操
Fuck!
还有谁知道你们今天要去对付肯波的事
Who else knew today was the day you were moving on Kimber?
你说过你守口如瓶了  你还告诉谁了
You said you kept it a secret. Who else did you tell?
只有一件事能蒙蔽像你这么聪明的人  汤米
There's only one thing can blind a man as smart as you, Tommy.
爱
Love.
是那个酒吧女招待干的
It was that barmaid.
格蕾丝的事我来处理
I'll deal with Grace.
如果你再看见她  可能会杀了她的
If you set eyes on her again, you might kill her.
想一走了之吗
Going for good?
我听说有麻烦了
I heard there was trouble.
人的本能是件很有意思的事
Instinct's a funny thing.
通常我可以看出一个人的品性  但对于你
See, normally I can tell about a person. But with you...
战斗即将开始  我们该离开这儿
Look, the fighting's about to begin. We should get out of here.
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
汤米也知道
Tommy knows as well.
实际上今早那个警察已经告诉他了
Turned out that copper as good as told him this morning.
不过我想听你亲口说
But I wanted to hear it from your own lips.
我是国王麾下的一个密探
I am an agent of the crown.
我有权使用武力逮捕你
I have the power to arrest and the right to use force.
所以  请你别挡道
So, please, step out of my way.
正如我所说  人的本能很有意思
Like I say, instinct's a funny thing.
你真的爱上汤米了  不是吗
You fell for Tommy for real, didn't you?
我的枪可是上了膛的
This gun is loaded.
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
我为你感到遗憾
I feel sorry for you.
真是个了不起的小丫头
Slip of a thing.
你竟以为可以深入这里  把我们一网打尽
Thought you'd come in here and stitch us all up.
没错  我们这儿是有几个警察的眼线  但你
I mean, we've had some copper's narks in here, but you?
你简直是其中的女王
You're the queen of them all.
你到底是谁
So, who are you?
我猜你是富家小姐  工会主义分子
Rich girl, I'd guess. Unionist.
阿尔斯特志愿军
Ulster Volunteer.
你觉得芬尼亚运动成员
You thought Fenians,
共产主义分子  低等人
Communists, low people...
他们都一个样  都是渣滓
they're all the same. Scum.
然后你遇到了汤米
Then you met Tommy.
我要用拳头跟你打一架
I'll fight you with my fists
让你看看富家小姐是怎么打架的
and show you how a rich girl fights.
我也来自一个艰苦的家庭
I'm from a tough family, too.
不了
Nah.
我们女人要理智一些
We women have more sense.
为什么不倒上两杯酒呢
Why don't you pour us both a drink?
我说对了吗
So, am I right?
你爱上了汤米吗
Did you fall for Tommy?
-是的  -那我为你感到惋惜
- Yes. - Then I pity you.
我觉得他会杀了我
I think he'll try to kill me.
-他太软弱了  -软弱
- He's too soft. - Soft?
和你一样  软弱
Soft. Like you.
警察来的那个晚上  你救了他的命
You saved his life the night the coppers came.
所以我们才能坐在这儿喝酒  而不是打架
That's why we're drinking, not fighting.
我们欠你的
We owe you.
他去法国前  是什么样子的
What was he like...before France?
他经常笑
He laughed, a lot.
他喜欢和马一起相处
He wanted to work with horses.
他赢了不少奖章
He won medals.
都扔进切割机里去了
Threw them in the cut.
没有一个人从战场回来后还和从前一样
Ah, not a single man came back the same.
在这一切结束后
You know, after all this is over...
他也许会原谅你
He might forgive you.
他也许会接受你
He might take you in.
你永远无法知道男人会做出什么事
You can never tell with men.
他们的喜好全凭肉欲
They go for whoever their dicks point at,
他们的想法永不会变
and there's no changing their minds.
但我告诉你
But I should tell you something.
我永远不会原谅你
I will never forgive you.
不会接受你
or accept you.
也不会接纳你
or take you in.
在这个家里  我掌控着大家的心理
And it's me who runs the business of the heart in this family.
而对我来说  你是来自警方的探子
And as far as I'm concerned, you're a snitch from the Parish.
在明天之前如果你不从这个城市消失
And if you're not gone from this city by tomorrow...
我会亲自杀了你
I'll kill you myself.
现在  你走吧
Now, go.
也许真正使你心烦的是
Maybe what really upsets you
你觉得总有一天你可能会失去他
is the thought that one day you might lose him.
汤米
Tommy.
我们听海米尔斯那边的伙计说
We've had word from Nipper at Hay Mills,
是警察放他们通行的
and he says the police are letting them through.
警察怎么都消失了
And how come all our police have disappeared?
因为把我们的计划告诉肯波的正是警察
Because it was the police who told Kimber about our plan.
是谁告诉警察的
And who told the police?
你知道吗  约翰
You know what, John?
虽然我觉得自己挺聪明
For all I think I'm the smart one...
但我猜  是我走漏了风声
I'm guessing it was me.
好了  兄弟们
All right, men...
你们大多经历过战争
You were mostly in the war,
所以你们知道作战方案经常变动
so you know that battle plans always change
经常被搞砸
and get fucked up.
现在情况正是如此  计划有变
Well, here it is. Things have changed.
我们要在这里和他们战斗
We fight them here.
今天  孤军奋战
Today. Alone.
挺好  他们会向酒吧发动进攻
Now, they're going to come for the pub.
他们想让我们永世不得翻身
They're going to try to break us up for good.
今天  警察也对我们弃之不顾
And we'll have no help from the law today.
那家酒吧叫做加里森[堡垒]
That pub there is called the Garrison.
现在它是名副其实的堡垒了
Well, now it really is one.
它是属于我们的  对吗
And it belongs to us, right?
对
Right!
他们有多少人
How many are there?
贾玛尔说有两辆莱利大蓬货车
Jeremiah says two Riley vans.
估计我们要一对三
So I reckon we're outnumbered three to one.
操他娘的
Ah... Fuck.
但兄弟们  我们可是小希斯步枪
But it's us, boys. It's us. The Small Heath Rifles.
-我们战无不胜  是不是  -是
- Never lost a fight yet, did we? - No!
好  贾玛尔
All right. Jeremiah.
我知道你向上帝发誓绝不再动武
I know you vowed to God to never pick up a weapon again.
但你能代我问问他  你今天会帮助我们吗
But can you ask him from me if you can help us today?
上帝说  他不管小希斯  先生
God says he don't deal with Small Heath, sir.
好样的
Good man.
亚瑟  斯卡德伯特  你们负责侧翼
Arthur, Scudboat. You take the flanks.
-跟在圣玛丽时一样  -是
- Just like at St Marie. - Sir.
科利  任何一个谢尔比家的人今天死在这里
Curly, if any Shelby man dies here today,
你都要把我们埋在一起
you bury us side by side.
好吧  我们大概还有10分钟
All right. We've about ten minutes.
找个人做临终忏悔去吧
Make your peace with whoever.
我们收到线报称有一大群人坐车
We've had a report of a large group of men in vehicles
往城里来了
heading towards the city.
他们中的大多数都是警察熟悉的惯犯  长官
Most of them are known to the police, sir.
我们认为即将爆发一场黑帮火拼
We think a gang fight's about to break out.
我要以下地点的
I want all officers and
所有官员和巡警全部撤退
constables stood down in the following areas.
博德斯黎  小希斯  夏德坊  格雷特
Bordesley, Small Heath, Shard End, Greet...
和海米尔斯
and Hay Mills.
-撤退吗  先生  -立刻
- Stood down, sir? - Immediately.
不要阻止这些车进城
And the vehicles approaching the city should not be impeded.
到底是什么情况
What the hell is going on?
狗咬狗去吧
Let dog eat dog.
让他们斗个两败俱伤
Let the beasts devour each other.
我们再渔翁得利吧
And then we shall pick the bones.
她走了吗
She's gone, then?
你不习惯
You're not accustomed to
得不到你想要的东西  对吧  汤米
not getting what you want, are you, Tommy?
你想得到我的酒吧  你就拿去了
You wanted my pub and you took it.
你卖了个好价钱
You got a fair price.
我只得到一纸最后通牒
What I got was an ultimatum.
你给别人下的全是最后通牒
Like you give to everybody.
别敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Do it, or else.
但有意思的是
And yet, it's funny.
这里的每个人  都希望你赢得这场战斗
Everybody round here, they want you to win this battle.
我想是因为
I think, what it is...
你是个坏人  但你是我们的坏人
you're bad men, but you're our bad men.
你会去找她吗
Will you go looking for her?
她已经成为过去了
She's in the past.
我不关心过去
The past is not my concern.
也不再关心未来
The future is no longer my concern, either.
那你关心什么  汤米
What is your concern, Tommy?
一分钟
The one minute.
士兵的一分钟
The soldier's minute.
在战斗中  你只有这一分钟时间
In a battle, that's all you get.
一切都在这一分钟内爆发
One minute of everything at once.
此前的一切都成虚无
And anything before is nothing.
此后的一切
Everything after...
也都是虚无
nothing.
什么都比不上
Nothing in comparison...
那一分钟
to that one minute.
你在那里经历的次数还不够多吗
Didn't you get enough minutes over there?
好像是不够  不是吗
Seems not, doesn't it?
汤米  他们来了
Tommy, they're here.
掏出家伙  兄弟们  装上子弹
Get your weapons out, boys, and load 'em up.
慢慢来
Take your time.
都给我举着  让那些人瞧瞧我们的武器装备
Hold 'em up in the air so as they can see what we've got.
有枪没种是吧  比利小子们
All guns and no balls, right, Billy boy?
那我们现在要怎么做
So, what do we do now?
下命令吧
Just give the order.
到达加里森街的那些人都配有步枪
The men that have arrived in Garrison Lane are armed with rifles.
你听到我说的话了吗
Did you hear me?
我不关心他们如何自我毁灭
Their methods of self-destruction are not my concern.
我们还收到线报说萨尔特利有人使出机关枪了
Well, we've also had report of machine gun fire in Saltleigh.
不过是患有弹震症的老兵在胡说八道
The ravings of an old soldier with shell shock.
25挺刘易斯机关枪我们只找到了24挺
We only found 24 of those 25 Lewis guns.
如果他们要是用了这一挺
If they were to get to use the one...
当时...
You know, when, er...
你从贝尔法斯特来这里的时候  我欣喜若狂
when you came here from Belfast I was overjoyed.
我受够了这里的警界  受够了这里的腐败堕落
I was sick of this force, and I was sick of all the corruption.
你演讲声称要肃清这里的时候
When you made that speech about cleaning this place up,
我心里一阵欢呼
I gave a little cheer inside.
你说只有恶魔才会睁一只眼闭一只眼
You said it was the devil's work to look the other way.
我没有睁一只眼闭一只眼  莫斯警官
I am not looking the other way, Sergeant Moss.
我一直在盯着今天要发生的事情
I am looking directly at the events of the day.
那正是我喜闻乐见的
And I like what I see.
没必要闹到这步田地  肯波
It doesn't have to be like this, Kimber.
一切都太迟了
Too late for all that.
你贪心不足导致大祸临头  小杂种
You've bit off more than you can chew, you little toerag.
所以我要来接管这个鬼地方了
And now I'm going to take over this shithole.
如果非得用枪
We have to use guns...
那就得用好枪
let's use proper guns.
索恩军士前来报道  长官
Sergeant Thorne reporting for duty, sir.
你刚刚不是说枪比我们多吗
You were saying something about being out-gunned.
让开
Move!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我想你们管这里叫无人地带没错吧
I believe you boys call this "No-man's land."
-艾达  -闭嘴听我说
- Ada... - Shut up and listen.
-你疯了吗  -我说了闭嘴
- Have you lost your mind? - I said shut up!
你们中大多数人都去过法国参战
Now, most of you were in France.
所以你们一定知道接下来会怎么样
So you all know what happens next.
我的兄弟和丈夫此刻都站在这里
I've got brothers and a husband here
也一定有人在等着你们
but you've all got somebody waiting for you.
我提前穿上丧服做准备
Now, I'm wearing black in preparation.
我要你看着我
I want you to look at me.
我要你们都看着我
I want you all to look at me.
谁会为你们穿丧服
Who'll be wearing black for you?
想想他们
Think about them.
现在就想想他们
Think about them right now.
还想斗就斗吧  但我不会移走这孩子的
And fight if you want to, but that baby ain't moving anywhere.
我也不走
And neither am I.
她说得对
She's right, you know.
你们凭什么要死
Why should all you men die?
只有导致这一切的那个人该死
It should just be them who's caused it.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你没事的  孩子  你没事的
You're all right, son. You're all right.
艾达  快走开
Ada, move away.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
把枪举起来
Hold your guns up!
够了
Enough.
这场战斗由肯波和我单挑
Kimber and me fought this battle one on one.
现在一切结束了
It's over.
回去找你们的家人吧
Go home to your families.
斯卡德伯特  科利  把他抬起来
Scudboat, Curly...pick him up.
我想问你一个问题  之后我就会离开
I want to ask you one question. Then I'll leave.
汤米知道我是谁  你跟他说什么了
Tommy knows who I am. What did you say to him?
你跟他说什么了
What did you say to him?
我告诉他
I told him...
他会在明天之前心碎
..that his heart would be broken before the day was over.
所以看来
So, it seems...
你弄碎了两个人的心  格蕾丝
You've broken two hearts, Grace.
我自己的心也碎了
As well as my own.
坚持  汤米  坚持
That's it, Tommy, that's it.
坚持住  汤米
Bite it, Tommy.
拿出来  快拿出来
Take it. Take it!
-按住他  -坚持
- Hold him still. - That's it, lad.
加油  加油
Come on. Come on!
取出来了  我还是宝刀未老
There! I still have the knack.
喝一口
Have a drink.
好  深呼吸
Right, deep breath.
好了  结束了
That's it. It's done.
现在可以好好把他葬在
Now we can bury him properly
之前为他挖的坟墓里了
in the grave we dug for him.
在高高的山坡上  他会喜欢的
It's high on a hill. He'll like that.
-敬高速炮弹丹尼  -丹尼
- To Danny Whizz-Bang. - Danny.
愿所有人都可以死两次
May we all die twice.
敬高速炮弹丹尼
To Danny Whizz-Bang.
高速炮弹丹尼
Danny Whizz-Bang.
走吧
Come on.
今天是我们的大好日子  去庆祝吧
The day is ours, let's celebrate.
怎么样
Well?
谁赢了
Who won?
找到了威廉·肯波被人枪杀的尸体
A Mr William Kimber has been found dead with a gunshot wound.
所以我猜是剃刀党赢了
So, I'm guessing that means the Peaky Blinders won.
长官
Sir.
另外  那个共党分子  弗莱迪·索恩
Also, the communist agitator Freddie Thorne
在押运期间被人持枪劫走了
was taken from his transport by armed men.
由于当时街上没有警察
Since there were no police officers on the street at the time...
那完全是遵照您的命令
following your orders...
他轻松逃掉了  现在逍遥法外
he managed to escape easily and is now at large.
狱警说他认出了劫持他的人
The prison officers said they recognised the men.
也是剃刀党的人  长官
They were Peaky Blinders as well, sir.
我们可以去抓几个人来问问
I mean, we could go down there and make a few arrests
但肯定问不出什么
but, er, no-one will have seen anything.
而且因为没有其他警官做证人  所以
And there were no officers there to witness, so...
谢尔比家的人连谋杀罪都可以逃掉了
The Shelbys will get away with murder.
就像以前一样
Just like they always have.
有些事是不会变的
Some things never change.
对吗  长官
Eh, sir?
敬
A toast...
敬谢尔比有限公司
A toast, to Shelby Limited!
谢尔比
Shelby!
他有几个儿子  我们该帮他们找个工作吗
He's got sons. Should we find work for them?
不  让他们自由发展吧
No. Let them be.
让他们找个普通的工作  做个普通的人
Let them find ordinary work like ordinary men.
请帮我接丘吉尔先生
Could you put me through to Mr Churchill, please?
长官
Yes, sir.
Sir...
我为我的仕途做了一个决定
I have made a decision about my future.
所有人都要走了
Everyone's leaving town.
-汤米你受伤了  -我没事
- Tommy, you're hurt. - I'm fine.
我该说什么
What exactly can I say?
我不知道  格蕾丝
I don't know, Grace.
我可以告诉你我的真实身份
I could tell you who I really am.
我觉得我已经知道了
I think I know who you are.
你也知道我
And you know who I am.
琐事细节并不重要
The circumstance is not important.
-琐事细节  -仅此而已
- Circumstance? - Is all it is.
那只是公事
Just uniform.
总有一天我会把枪扔进大运河
Someday I will throw this gun in the canal.
为什么现在不行
Why not now?
但爱就是这么来了  汤米
Here it comes, Tommy.
我爱你
I love you.
也就这么散去了  格蕾丝
And there it goes, Grace.
就这样散去
Away it goes.
我们不管再说多少次
We can say it as much as we like...
也是不可能的
But there's no chance.
我会在伦敦呆一周  地址在这里
I'll be in London one week. This address.
忙完这里的事然后来找我
Finish your business here and join me.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
-他来了  汤米  -要酒吗
- There he is... Tommy. - Drink?
不要威士忌
Not whisky.
你看吧台后面
If you check behind the bar...
有一瓶香槟
you will find a bottle of champagne.
是她买的
The one she bought.
今天是个好日子
Today was a good day.
当肯波的人都聚在这里的时候
All of Kimber's men were busy here,
李家的人抢到了所有乌斯特比赛的操控权
so the Lee boys took all the pitches at the Worcester races.
简直比事先安排的还好
It couldn't have gone better if we'd planned it.
谢尔比兄弟有限公司
Shelby Brothers Limited
现在是这个国家
are now the third largest
第三大的合法赌马公司
legal race track operation in the country.
干杯  只有萨比利公司
Cheers! Only the Sabinis
和所罗门公司在我们之上
and the Solomons are bigger than us, boys.
我所有家人都在此庆祝
And all my family is here to celebrate.
敬谢尔比兄弟有限公司
To Shelby Brothers Limited.
谢尔比  兄弟
Shelby! Brothers!
干杯
Cheers.
还有其它人
There'll be others.
敬其它人
To the others.
所有人
All of them.
谢尔比兄弟有限公司
亲爱的格蕾丝
Dear Grace...
没有了秘书  我只能亲手写这封信
Without a secretary, I write my own letters
我对你毫无恨意
and I write without malice.
我很久前就学会憎恨我的敌人
I learnt long ago to hate my enemies.
却从没爱过任何人
But I've never loved one before.
一起去纽约的主意很棒
The idea of New York is interesting
但我为了今天的胜利  努力了很久
but I have worked so hard for this day, for this victory.
我在这里肩负着重要责任
I have responsibilities here
要去保护那些需要保护的人  和我爱的人
for people I need to protect and people who I love.
战争之前  当我需要做重大决定的时候
Before the war, when I had an important decision to make,
我喜欢扔硬币
I used to flip a coin.
也许这次也要这样决定了
Perhaps that is what I will do again.
波莉告诉我  你是真的爱上我了
Polly tells me you fell in love for real
她对这种事的直觉向来都是准的
and Polly is never wrong about matters of the heart.
我会在三天内告诉你我的决定
I will give you my decision within three days.
爱你的  汤玛斯·谢尔比
All my love. Tommy Shelby.